我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友  我只能伪装成另一个人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
深切怀念托马斯·梅林
孝子
成为另一种存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
你能说你没有滥用药物吗
You're telling me you don't have a substance abuse problem?
地检办给了一笔很可观的解雇补偿金
The D.A.'s office has a generous severance package.
等等  我去跟检察官亲自解释一下好吗
Wait, let me explain to the D.A.--
对不起  但是你被解雇了
I'm sorry, but you're done.
是时候做出选择了  奥利弗
Time to choose, Oliver,
选出谁生  谁死
who lives and who dies.
你拿到了你想要的东西
You got what you came for!
-时间到  -你这变态的神经病
- Time's up. - You freaking psychopath!
不  不
No, no!
不
No!
罗伊被注射了血清
Roy was injected with the serum.
我们得看着他
We are going to have to keep an eye on him.
罗伊  停下  他快死了
Roy! Stop it, you're killing him!
现在你更快更强了
You're stronger, you heal faster,
但是你却控制不了自己
but you're not in control.
我可以教你  让我帮你吧
I can teach you. Let me help you.
我们什么时候开始
When do we start?
给你带来个新客人
Got your latest customer.
这位天才竟然去抢
Genius who held up the convenience store
警局对面的便利店
across the street from a police precinct.
这计划可不明智
Not the smartest plan.
走过来
Come on through.
膝盖有伤
Bum knee.
几年前动过手术
I had it replaced a few years ago.
那还是用老办法吧
Well, I guess we'll have to do this old-fashioned-like.
抬起胳膊
Arms up.
给你找了个新狱友
Got your new bunk mate.
别惹事
Play nice.
你是本·特纳吗
Ben Turner?
今晚
Tonight.
午夜  红林路和燕草大道
Midnight. Redwood Drive and Larkspur Avenue.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
红林路和燕草大道  屋顶  去那里
Redwood and Larkspur. The rooftop. Be there.
你没四下看看吗
I don't know if you've looked around,
我们没法自由出入这地方
but we don't exactly have in and out privileges here.
我儿子跟他妈在一起
My son is with his mother.
反正我是再也见不到他了
I won't get to see him, anyway.
这样做  他就没事
This way, he's set.
我完成这事  他就能拿到钱
I do this, he gets the money.
完成什么
Do what?
这里怎么回事
What's going on down there?
该死
Crap.
你把他怎么了
What the hell did you do to him?
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
绿箭
第二季第十二集
再来
Again.
我昨天是在拍水
You know, I slapped water out of a bowl yesterday.
前天也是在拍水
And I slapped water out of a bowl the day before.
你肯定很擅长了
You must be getting pretty good at it.
是啊  我已经等不及被狗粮攻击了
Yeah, well, I can't wait to get attacked by a dog dish.
这是射手锻炼臂力的方法
This is how an archer builds arm strength.
你难道不知道吗
I'm not sure if you've been paying attention,
力量对我来说不是问题
but strength isn't my problem.
对  但控制力量是你的问题
No, controlling it is.
再来
Again.
就因为这样
And that...
你上周才把一个人打到进医院
is how you put a guy in the hospital last week.
你怎么知道的
How'd you know about that?
这事跟你没关系
It's none of your business.
你答应让我帮你的时候
You made it my business
这事就跟我有关系了
when you agreed to let me help you.
我以前认识一个像你这样的人
I knew someone like you.
注射了米拉库鲁的人
Someone injected with the Mirakuru.
他是我的朋友
He was my friend.
但是这血清扭曲了他的心智
But it warped his mind to the point
以至于我都认不出他了
where I didn't even recognize him anymore.
这人是谁
Who was this guy?
我怎么从没听说过他
How come I've never heard of him?
也没听说过米拉库鲁
Or that Mirakuru?
还有什么他的事你能告诉我吗
Is there anything you can tell me about him?
是的
Yeah.
我用一支箭射穿了他的眼
I had to put an arrow through his eye.
如果我没看错的话  斯莱德在洞里
If I'm reading this right, then Slade is back at the cave.
他为什么要去墓地那里
Well, why would he go back to where the graves are?
找到他就知道了
We'll find out when we find him.
找到他的时候  你不能跟他说
And when we do... you can't tell him.
说什么
Tell him what?
别对我像个外人似的
Don't talk to me like I'm other people.
你脸上就是这种表情
You've got that look on your face.
我们第一次接吻时就是这种表情
The same one that you had after the first time we kissed.
纯粹内疚的表情
Pure guilt.
因为我就是很内疚  莎拉
Because I am guilty, Sara.
因为我  艾沃才杀了莎朵
Ivo killed Shado because of me.
不是这样的
But that's not true.
就算是这样
And even if it was,
你告诉斯莱德是因为你
nothing good comes from telling Slade
害死了他爱的女人
that you think you're responsible
对你没有任何好处
for the death of the woman he loved.
爱是最强大的情感
Love's the most powerful emotion.
因此它也是最危险的
And that makes it the most dangerous.
说得真好
Great.
你知道怎么去洞穴吗
You still know how to get to the cave?
是的
Yeah.
这条路
It's this way.
西娅
Thea?
你怎么在家
What are you doing home?
我以为你留在罗伊家了
I thought you were staying at Roy's.
我想自己待一会
Just needed a little "me" Time.
怎么穿得这么隆重
What's with the fancy fancy?
我  我要出去吃饭
Oh, I'm-- I'm going out to dinner.
跟沃尔特一起
With Walter.
算是约会吗
Like a date?
只是吃晚饭
Like a dinner.
说实话  我也不知道今晚算什么
Truly, I don't know what the evening holds.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
是的  我没事
Yeah. I'm fine.
主要是
Mostly. Uh...
罗伊的事
It's Roy.
他上周遇上点麻烦
He had some trouble last week, and...
而我不知道怎么帮他
I don't know how to help him.
你想让我留在家里吗
Do you want me to stay home?
我可以给沃尔特打个电话  重新再约
I can call Walter and we can reschedule.
当然不用
Absolutely not.
如果你和沃尔特准备重归于好
If you and Walter are going to patch things up...
不给你压力  但你一定要去
No pressure. But you're going.
可能没什么
It may be nothing.
只有一个办法才能知道
Only one way to find out.
不介意  老爸  进来吧
No, please, dad, come right in.
看来你已经把房子住得很破烂了
Well, I guess you're going for that lived-in look.
没有工作请不起管家
Can't afford a housekeeper without a job.
酒钱倒是挺足的
Got enough beverage money, I see.
如果你想吵架
I'm going to need to crack
那就先让我再开一瓶酒吧
open another bottle if we're going to fight.
我不是来吵架的
I didn't come here to fight.
那你来干什么
Then why are you here?
我过得挺好的  真的
Because I'm fine, really.
实际上  我有个工作面试
In fact, I have a job interview.
是乔安娜的新公司
At Joanna's new firm.
挺好的  不错
That's good. Good.
但我来这里的真正原因是
But the real reason I came here is--
是你觉得你需要每周定量的来
Is because you realized that you didn't reach your weekly quota
揭示我的生活如何不堪
of reminding me of how much I'm ruining my life?
是因为我想你了  劳蕾尔
It's 'cause I miss you, Laurel.
长久以来  我们相依为命
For a long time, it was just you and me.
不管发生什么
Whatever else was going on,
不管对方有多糟糕
no matter how bad either of us was doing,
我们谁都不会不管对方
we didn't disappear on each other.
你是我的家人
Because you're my family.
而我想念我的家人
And I miss my family.
所以要不要一起吃个晚餐
So how about we have dinner?
你和我  今晚
You and me, tonight.
我已经吃过了
I already ate.
好吧
Yeah.
那明晚呢
How about tomorrow night?
可以
Sure.
明晚晚餐
Dinner tomorrow.
谢谢
Thank you.
和罗伊怎么样了
How's it going with Roy?
不怎么样
Not well!
我跟这孩子不熟
I don't know the kid all too well,
但是他看起来充满了愤怒
but he seems to be five kinds of angry.
你低估他了
You might be underestimating.
罗伊在注射米拉库鲁前就很愤青了
Roy was mad at the world before he was injected with Mirakuru.
你说你有过类似经历
You say you've seen this before?
斯莱德·威尔逊  他曾是我朋友
Slade Wilson. He was my friend.
你故意使用了过去时
Troubling use of past tense there.
我觉得我可以帮助他控制住
I thought I could help him control it.
但我错了
I was wrong.
但是现在我知道的更多了  我不会在
But I know more now, and I'm not going
罗伊身上犯同样的错误了
to make the same mistake with Roy.
是什么
What's that?
铁山监狱  鉴于他们那可悲的安保能力
Iron Heights. Due to their low security post-quake,
我觉得应该花些时间监视一下
I thought it would be a good idea to keep an eye on
他们的内部通讯系统
their internal communication for a while.
你黑进了监狱内部系统
You hacked into a prison system network?
你是在批判我吗
Is that judgment I'm hearing?
骄傲
Pride.
铁山监狱刚对本·特纳下了通牒
Iron Heights just put out a bolo for Ben Turner,
也就是青铜虎  顺便说一句
Aka Bronze Tiger, which, btw,
这真是个烂绰号  老虎不是青铜色的
is a terrible nickname, because tigers are not bronze.
特纳逃跑了
Turner escaped?
出去时杀了十个守卫
Killed ten guards on his way out.
这事肯定会上新闻
You think that would have made the news.
铁山监狱保密的能力
Iron Heights is better at keeping secrets
比他们看管囚犯的能力强多了
than they are at keeping prisoners.
知道他可能去哪吗
Any idea where he's headed?
不知道
No.
找出来
Get one.
叫你们的人到别处去
Tell your men to take a walk.
走开
Leave us.
武器可以放在这
They can leave their weapons, too.
感谢您的提前释放
Thank you for the early release.
本来想就这么走的  但是我
Thought about taking off, but I'm...
很好奇
curious.
谁会帮个陌生人逃狱啊
Who would break a stranger out of prison?
想让那罪犯帮忙的人
Someone who wishes to hire you for a job.
我需要帮忙找回一样东西
I need you to help my men retrieve a certain item.
就是这个
This is the item.
你见过  对吧
You know it, yes?
确实
Yes, I do.
你知道还缺什么吗
Do you know what you're missing with here?
不菲的价格
Won't be cheap.
钱不是问题
This is not a problem.
你知道它有百人以上的杀伤力吧
You do know that thing could kill hundreds of people?
不对  特纳先生
No, Mr. Turner.
是千人以上
It will kill thousands.
该你了
Now you.
慢慢来
Go slowly.
停
Stop!
我不是在教你出拳
This is not about learning to throw a punch,
是在教你力度控制
this is about learning to control your strength.
先是打水花  现在又是这个
First water slapping, now this.
你什么时候才能玩完这些
When are you going to run out of ways
让我看起来很蠢的把戏
to make me look stupid?!
我能学到的就只有怎么被惹毛
All I'm learning is new ways to get pissed off,
顺便说一句
and in case you haven't noticed,
我本来就擅长被惹毛
I'm already pretty good at that.
愤怒并非无益  罗伊  力量就来自愤怒
There's nothing wrong with anger, Roy. Anger is energy,
但是你得学习用好的方式使用它
but you need to learn to channel it in a positive way.
比如打击那些破坏城市的人
Like putting the hurt on guys going after the city.
就不让我打个能反击的目标吗
Let me try hitting something that'll actually hit back.
时候未到
Too soon.
带我去一次
Get me out there with you.
就一晚上
One night.
这些蠢东西也能好接受些
All this, it would be a lot easier to take.
莫伊拉
Moira.
我以为是二人晚餐呢
Ah. I didn't realize we'd have company.
这位是马克·弗朗西斯
This is Mark Frances.
他是卡达克集团的首席财务官
Mark's CFO at Kardak Holdings.
我们曾在政党选举指导委员会共事过
We've been putting in some hours with the party's election steering committee.
很高兴见到你
It's a pleasure to meet you.
最近高兴见我的人可不多了
Those are words I'm not accustomed to hearing these days.
你只是像母狮一样在保护自己的孩子们
You were a lioness doing what she had to do to protect her cubs.
星城很多人都像我一样
You know, I'm not the only person in Starling
站在你这边
who sees it that way.
谢谢你的安慰
That's a comfort.
实话实说而已  请坐
It's the truth. Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
不常见你对政治
Well, it's unlike you to
如此兴趣浓厚呢  沃尔特
show such an interest in politics, Walter.
这是我星城国家银行新工作的一部分
It's part of my new position at the Starling National Bank.
董事会很关注
My board of directors is very concerned
星城的发展方向
about the trajectory of the city.
-你是说塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德  -是的
- You mean Sebastian Blood. - Yeah.
我们相信他的政策会让
We believe that his policies will bankrupt Starling
星城在八个月之内破产
within the next eight months.
但平常选民却不关注此事
Not that the average voter cares.
他们都被他的魅力俘获了
They're all caught up in his charisma.
而且没有可以与他匹敌的对手
And he's not running against a viable opponent.
他打败了我们所有重点培养的候选人
Blood's trounced every potential candidate we've focus-tested.
不过制度方面是他的弱项
But we believe that he's vulnerable on regulation.
就算是又能怎样呢
Even if he is, it hardly matters.
银行政策只是证交会的问题
Banking regulations are an SEC issue.
星城需要的是城市层面的对抗
Starling City needs to use the means at a city's disposal.
沃尔特说过你很聪明
Walter said you were smart.
但你没邀请我吃晚餐  听我的意见
But you didn't invite me to dinner to hear my opinions.
你想了解我的位置
You want to hear my positions.
你想让我去对抗塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德
You want me to run against Sebastian Blood.
爸  我快饿死了  我们要去哪儿
Dad, I'm starving. Where are we going?
就在这儿有个小店
It's little hole in the wall right here.
劳蕾尔  等一下
Laurel, wait.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
我真不敢相信你会做这样的事情
I can't believe you would do something like this.
否则你也不会来呀
Well, you wouldn't have come otherwise.
你说对了
Well, you got that right.
劳蕾尔  你需要帮助
Laurel, you need help.
那也用不着他们
Not from them.
那间屋子里没有一个人
There is not one person in that room
知道我所经历的痛苦
who knows what I have been through.
你说的没错  他们之中有人承受过比你更痛苦的事情
Yeah, you're right. Some of them, they've been through worse.
但是不管怎样
But for better or worse,
每一个人走进那间屋子都是因为需要
everyone in that room needs to be there,
现在你也需要去那
and you need to be there.
你以为只有你失去过爱人吗
You think you're the only person that's ever lost someone?
只有你被炒过鱿鱼  只有你曾经把生活搞的一团糟吗
Who ever got fired, who ever got their lives into a mess?
孩子  你好好想想  不是只有你最惨
You think again, kiddo, 'cause you're not.
你看  现在我们已经来了
Now, look, we're here now.
那你为什么不能呆一会儿呢
So why don't you just stay for a bit?
你不需要跟别人说你的事  你只需要倾听
You don't have to share or talk. You just listen.
我已经说的很清楚了
I thought I made myself clear.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
我还是一个人去吃饭吧
And now I think I'll eat alone.
说吧
Go ahead.
星城警署网站刚刚公布了一起谋杀案
SCPD's network just lit up with a fresh homicide,
死者身上有多处刺伤  像是爪子弄的
Multiple stab wounds. Like claw marks.
受害人是一名建筑师
The victim was an architect.
特纳洗劫了他的住所  拿走了他设计的图纸
Turner ransacked his place; took blueprints of his designs.
他是马尔科姆·梅林的房子的设计者之一
One of the aforementioned designs--Malcolm Merlyn's house.
我对建筑学不太了解  但我知道这不是好事
I don't know much about architecture, but this can't be good.
特纳想从梅林的房子得到什么
What would Turner want with Merlyn's house?
现在还不清楚  马尔科姆的所有产业
Not sure yet. All of Malcolm's holdings,
包括那栋房子  都处于破产受管状态
including the house, are in receivership.
你在和谁讲话
Who's that you're talking to?
等等  让我猜猜  这个你也不能告诉我
Oh, wait, let me guess, you can't tell me that, either.
一个被我送进监狱的人越狱了
A guy that I put in prison got out,
而我知道他会去哪
and I have an idea where he's headed.
你有连帽衫吗
Do you have one of your hoodies?
这还用问吗
Do you seriously have to ask?
无论发生什么事  无论遇到什么人
Whatever happens, whoever we run into,
都不要理会
do not engage.
什么也不要碰
And don't touch anything.
这是他的孩子  对吗
This is his kid, right?
死掉的那个人的孩子
The guy that died?
是
Yes.
你很熟悉这里
You know your way around this place.
你之前来过这儿吗
You been here before?
那是什么
What was that?
声音是从地下传出来的
It came from underground.
梅林有一个大的地下车库
Merlyn has a large garage.
咱们走
Let's go.
这到底是什么
What the hell is that?
看起来像个原型机
Looks like a prototype.
什么的原型机
Of what?
一个曾经杀死了503个人的机器的原型机
A machine that killed 503 people.
梅林自己的地震设备
Merlyn's own earthquake device.
好了  如探囊取物般简单
Ok, a simple snatch and grab.
不明白为什么阿米蒂奇先生要让你跟着
Don't know why Mr. Armitage thought we needed you.
因为他们
For that.
离那台设备远点
Step away from the device.
你们不知道你们拿的是什么
You don't know what it is you're dealing with.
不就是一台能制造地震的大机器吗
Big machine, makes earthquakes?
如果它落到居心不良的人手中
Do you have any idea what happens
你知道会发生什么事吗
if the wrong people have it?
知道  我收钱了
Yeah. I get paid.
关好门
Close it up.
那台机器杀了我8个朋友
That thing killed eight of my friends.
够了
That's enough!
你看起来很生气
Uh-oh. You got angry face.
发生了什么事
What happened?
罗伊·哈珀
Roy Harper.
你带他出去了
You took him out in the field--
狄格尔  他没听我的话
He wasn't listening to me, Diggle!
我试图要抓住他  但他失去了控制
I'm trying to reach him, but he lost control.
他差点杀了人
Then he nearly killed somebody,
我当然不能让他这么干  在这过程中
which I obviously couldn't let happen, and in the process--
特纳跑了
Turner got away.
他去那偷什么  梅林的艺术收藏品吗
What was he there to steal? Merlyn's art collection?
比那要危险的多的东西
Something much more dangerous.
是一台地震机的样机
It's a prototype earthquake machine.
天呐
Oh, holy god.
为什么特纳要毁掉这座城市
Why would Turner want to destroy the city?
他没有  他是一个雇佣兵
He doesn't. He's a mercenary
他为出价最高的人服务
Selling his services to the highest bidder.
这块表是其中一个
This watch belonged to one of the guys
-和特纳一起工作的人的  -有指纹
- Turner was working with. - Fingerprints.
特纳是个独行者  这意味着手表的主人为特纳的客户工作
Turner's a loner, which mean that guy works for his client.
有了指纹就等于知道了名字  等于知道了他的同伙
Fingerprints equals name, equals known associates.
我马上查
I'm on it.
在罗伊眼中看到的神情
It was the look in Roy's eyes.
和斯莱德眼中的一模一样
It was Slade all over again.
奥利弗  斯莱德发生了什么事
Oliver, what happened with Slade?
我
Me.
有人杀了莎朵
Someone killed Shado.
斯莱德爱过莎朵  而这是我的错
Slade loved Shado, and it was my fault.
我想要告诉他
I wanted to tell him,
因为这从我口中说出比较好
because it would have been better coming from me,
但是我没有
but I didn't.
然后  他从其他途径知道了
And he found out another way.
如果我直接告诉了他真相
If I had just told him the truth,
我可能已经得到了他的谅解
I could have gotten through to him.
而这就是为什么  对你来说得到罗伊的谅解很重要
And that's why it's so important for you to get through to Roy.
我做了5年的噩梦
I lived a five year nightmare.
但如果我学到了什么
But if I learn something
让我现在能够了解罗伊
that could help me reach Roy now...
那所有的一切就都值得
it'll all be worth it.
他不在这儿
He's not here.
那他能去哪儿  我们已经检查过飞机了
Where else could he be? We already checked the plane.
我不知道
I don't know.
你记得之前见过这些吗
Do you remember seeing these before?
我没四处看过
I didn't really look around.
这些看起来很眼熟
They look familiar.
这可能是炼狱岛
This could be Lian Yu.
不  我是说这些演算
No, I mean the calculations.
我之前见过
I've seen those before.
可能是你第一次进山洞见到的
Maybe the first time you were in the cave.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
-法尔斯的发射器  -什么
- Fyer's launcher. - What?
去年有部队来过这个岛
Oh, there were soldiers on the island last year,
他们有一个导弹发射器  他们演示时
And they had a missile launcher. I saw one of these
我看到过其中一个   他们在进行发射计算
on the display. They're firing calculations...
他想要把那炸掉
He's going to blow it up.
把什么炸掉
Blow what up?
货船
The freighter.
谢天谢地你在这  我需要你帮忙
Oh, thank god you're here, I need your help--
我有话要跟你说  这很重要
I have to talk to you. It's important.
好  你看起来糟透了  没什么事吧
Ok. You look stressed out, is everything ok?
你得离开星城
You have to leave town.
可以的话  带上你妈跟你哥  现在就离开
Grab your mother and your brother, if you can, and leave.
几天就好
It's just for a few days.
能给个解释吗
A reason would be nice.
你得相信我  西娅
I need you to trust me, Thea.
我相信你  只是
I do. I just--
我们怎么能无缘无故就全家人离开呢
I can't up and leave with my family without a reason.
但你必须走
No, you have to.
罗伊  你说的我完全听不懂
Roy, you're not making any sense right now.
能告诉我到底发生了什么事吗
Would you just tell me what's going on?
你怎么不听我说呢
Why aren't you listening to me?
你得听我说
I need you to listen to me!
罗伊  你弄疼我了
Roy, you're hurting me!
我不是...不是...
I didn't...I didn't...
不是有意的  对不起
I didn't mean to. I'm sorry.
我知道
I know!
离开创新联合会后
Well. Your work environment
你的工作环境真是提高了不少
has definitely improved since CNRI.
这地方比我公寓还大呢
This place is bigger than my apartment!
不过外表的光鲜也是有局限的
Well, there is a limit to the glamour, unfortunately.
我整天都在处理文件
I spend my days in document production--
回答问询
and answering interrogatories.
感觉都不像是跟法律相关
It doesn't feel like practicing law so much as
而是做文书了
pushing papers.
如果我不了解的话  还真会以为
If I didn't know any better, I'd think
你是要说服我不干这份工作呢
that you were trying to talk me out of the job here.
看来我还是有点自知
I guess I do know better.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎么回事
What's going on?
这里的一位合伙人
One of the partners serves
是律师协会纪律委员会成员
on the Bar Association's Disciplinary Committee,
我把你的简历递上去时
and...well, when I sent your resume,
他做了些背景调查
he did some checking.
那完全是个误会
That was a complete misunderstanding.
没错  我是遇到了点麻烦
I mean, sure, yeah, I had some problems,
但我现在没事了
but I'm fine now.
律师协会要进行纪律听证会
The bar is going to open disciplinary proceedings.
为什么
What for?
确定你是否还有能力继续做律师
Conduct affecting your fitness to practice.
这真是  真是太荒谬了
That's-- that's ridiculous.
我知道
I know.
但在这事尘埃落地前
But while this is out there,
事务所不能雇佣你
the firm can't hire you.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你告诉我  我得走了
Thanks for letting me know. I have to go.
劳蕾尔  劳蕾尔
Laurel, Laurel.
你能度过这难关的  明白吗
You can fight this, ok?
我会帮助你
I'll help you, and--
我需要点时间来理清头绪
I need some time to...process.
我再打给你
I'll call you.
给你来点什么喝的
Can I fix you a drink?
跟你一样就行
Whatever you're having.
那晚上见到你很开心  莫伊拉
It was good to see you the other night, Moira.
的确不错
It was lovely.
我好久没这么开心地笑过了
It's been a while since I've had such a good laugh.
我们不是在说笑  莫伊拉
It was no joke, Moira.
马克说的是实话
Mark was telling the truth.
星城的很多人都觉得
A significant number of people in Starling City
你帮马尔科姆·梅林做事
feel that your actions with Malcolm Merlyn
是为了保护你的家人
were justified to protect your family.
事实上有43.6%的人这么认为
43.6%, in fact.
你对我发起民意测验
You polled people about me?
这是挑选候选人的
Prudent course of action when vetting
谨慎之举  没错
a potential candidate, yes.
星城有六十万人
600,000 people in Starling City.
我觉得你应该能找到一个
I'd think you could find someone not responsible
没用地震机毁坏它的人来竞选
for destroying it with an earthquake machine.
可你名声在外
Not with your name recognition.
我们需要一个能力挽狂澜的候选人  莫伊拉
We need a game change candidate, Moira.
而星城没有人比你更德高望重了
And there's no one in Starling with a higher profile than you.
查尔斯·曼森也挺有名的
Charles Manson is rather well-known,
曼森家族曾在加州领导着臭名昭著犯罪团伙
-可没人会投票给他  -没错
- and no one is going to vote for him. - True.
同样选民也喜欢自我救赎的故事
Equally true, voters like redemption stories.
比尔·克林顿  艾略特·斯皮策[前纽约市长]
Bill Clinton, Elliot Spitzer,
两人均被性丑闻缠身
玛莎·史都华
Martha Stewart.
美国家政女神 曾因内幕交易被判自家中软禁五个月
她可没参加过竞选
Oh, I don't believe she ran for office.
但如果她参加了  肯定会赢的
But if she had, she would have won.
会赢什么
Would have won what?
西娅
Ah, Thea.
怎么了
Mmm, what's going on?
我在劝你妈妈参加市长竞选
I'm just convincing your mother to run for mayor.
什么市长
Of what?
看到了吧
You see?
亲爱的  你还好吧
Sweetheart, are you all right?
你真的别再问这问题了
You really need to stop asking that.
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
我也知道这很难相信
It's hard to believe, I know.
不  并不是
No. No, it's not.
这其实会是我有投票权后的第一回竞选
Look, this is actually the first election I can vote in,
作为一个新手选民
and...as a newly minted voter,
我觉得这主意也不算太疯狂
I don't think it sounds that crazy.
听听你宝贝女儿说的话
From out of the mouths of babes.
你来晚了
You're late.
我想要我女朋友离开星城
I tried to get my girlfriend to leave town.
但她不肯
But she won't.
不准把她牵扯进来
You cannot bring her into this.
可我要怎么一边隐瞒着她
But how am I supposed to lie to her
一边保护她呢
and protect her at the same time?
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it?
你怎么对你生活中的人隐瞒事实真相
How do you keep secrets from people in your life?
只要记住这是唯一保证他们安全的办法
By remembering it's the only way to keep them safe.
不  要让他们安全才能保证安全
No, keeping them safe is what keeps them safe.
该告诉他们真相
Telling people the truth.
可你什么都不愿跟我说
But you, you won't tell me anything.
不说米拉库鲁  还有那个家伙
Not about the Mirakuru, and this other guy.
却让我在这傻子一样拍水跟打木头人
And you got me slapping water and hitting dummies instead.
罗伊  你现在太激动了  需要冷静下来
Roy, you're spiraling and you need to calm down.
不  我需要去救西娅
No. I need to save Thea.
都是因为你那家伙才跑出去了
That thing is out in the open because of you.
你帮的忙够多了
I think you've done enough.
放开我
Let go of me.
-罗伊  -我说了放开我
- Roy... - I said let go of me!
控制一下你自己
Get control.
就算不为我  不为你自己
If not for me or yourself,
也为了西娅
then do it for Thea.
你他妈对西娅有什么了解
What the hell do you know about Thea?
别跟我说她
Don't you talk about her!
你闹够了没
Are you done?
不  我没够
No. I'm not done.
我要去阻止那家伙
I'm going to stop this thing.
你要是想阻止我  就试试
And if you want to stop me, try.
再给我一箭  来啊
Try putting another arrow in me. Go ahead.
我现在恢复得很快  但如果你挡我的路
'Cause I heal fast now. But you get in my way,
我就让你好好看看你所担心的
then I'll give you a good look at that anger you're so worried
我失去控制发怒会怎样
about me losing control of.
我说我们应该在这下面装一台X光机的时候
You both scoffed when I said we should invest
你们俩都嘲笑我
in an x-ray machine for down here.
你想要怎么处理罗伊
What do you want to do about Roy?
指纹查的怎么样了
Where are we with the fingerprint?
我略过了国内的机构
I struck out on domestic agencies,
现在在查国际刑警  中国公安
but I'm checking Interpol, PRC Public Security
以及俄罗斯内务部的数据库
and MVD databases now.
奥利弗  我知道你要帮罗伊  也知道为什么
Oliver, I know you've taken Roy on, and why,
但是罗伊  斯莱德  很多我共事过的人...
but Roy, Slade, a lot of guys I've served with...
有些人已经丧失心智了  伙计
Some people are just broken, man.
无药可救了
And nobody can put them back together.
我拒绝相信这些
I refuse to believe that.
我不会让发生在斯莱德身上的事
I'm not letting what happened
再发生到罗伊身上
to Slade happen to Roy.
我不会的
I'm not.
怎么了
Yeah.
你在俱乐部附近吗
Are you near the club?
离得很近  怎么了
I'm pretty close. Why?
劳蕾尔在这里
Laurel's here.
她看起来不太好
She doesn't look good.
劳蕾尔在楼上
Hey. Laurel's upstairs.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
能给我杯带橄榄的饮料吗
Can I get something with olives?
什么饮料无所谓  只要有很多橄榄就行
I don't care what it is, as long as there are a lot of olives.
咖啡怎么样
How about coffee?
咖啡和橄榄
Coffee and olives?
这组合不好
Bad combination.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
就是在这里发生的  是不是  大俱乐部
This is where it's happening, right? The big club?
给  你的马提尼  三颗橄榄
Here you go, martini, triple olives.
谢谢
Thanks.
劳蕾尔  回家吧
Laurel, go home.
西娅·奎恩告诉我
Thea Queen, telling me
够了就是够了
enough is enough.
现在有钱了
Now that is rich.
好吧
Fine.
取消我进你酒吧的资格
Bar me from your bar.
这是今天的主题  是吗
That's today's theme, right?
取消资格
Disbarment.
劳蕾尔  你被取消律师资格了吗
Laurel, are you being disbarred?
是的  看起来我的律师生涯结束了
Yeah, looks like my law career's over.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
或许西娅可以雇我当服务员
Maybe Thea here can hire me as a waitress.
或者  奥利  我可以给你当秘书
Or, Ollie, I could come be your secretary.
但这意味着你要解雇她
But that would mean you would have to fire her.
你好  劳蕾尔  你还好吗
Hi, Laurel. How are you?
你要借我的车吗
Did you need to borrow my car?
你的豪车坏了吗
Did your limo break down?
请帮她叫辆计程车
Get her a cab, please.
指纹在国际刑警数据库有
Fingerprint was in Interpol's database.
那家伙是米洛·阿米蒂奇的手下
The guy worked for Milo Armitage.
他是个黑市军火商
He's a black market arms merchant.
他想卖掉那仪器
He's trying to sell the device.
你去找找阿米蒂奇
I need you to search for any indication
在星城的任何蛛丝马迹
that Armitage is in Starling.
已经找了  他的船在星城码头
I already did. His ship filed a loading manifest
提交了一张装货单
at the Starling City docks.
我会把船号给你
I'll get you the slip number.
你好  我是奥利弗
Hi, it's Oliver.
我刚刚碰到劳蕾尔  她出事了
I just ran into Laurel, and something's wrong.
她需要你
She needs you.
斯莱德
Slade?
奥利弗
Oliver...
斯莱德
Slade!
回来
Get back!
我们知道你的目标是那艘船
We know you're targeting the boat.
我要把那混蛋
I'm going to send that son of a bitch
送到海底
to the bottom of the ocean.
你要毁掉我们离开这个岛的唯一出路
You're going to destroy our only way off of the island!
只要艾沃死了  那就行
As long as Ivo is dead, it's fine.
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do it.
后退  不然就帮我
Get back, or so help me,
我会放到你的
I will put you down!
妈妈  你在这儿干什么
Mom? What are you doing here?
我来征求一下你的意见
I came by to get your advice on something.
到我办公室来
Step into my office.
是选举的事  是不是
This is about the campaign, right?
你能想到参与这事非常的棒
It's really awesome you're thinking of doing this.
你说的某些话我一直挥之不去
You said something that stayed with me.
可能外面有投票人
The idea that there could be voters out there
不会立刻就让我卸任
that wouldn't dismiss me out of hand.
你的确经营着一家数十亿美元的公司
Well, you did run a multi-billion dollar company.
是啊  还做了一件毁了城市的事
Yes, and an undertaking that destroyed the city.
人们会慢慢忘记的
People will get over that.
你怎么能这么确定
What makes you so certain?
因为我就是
Because I did.
我能提个建议吗
Can I make a suggestion?
不要再因为觉得自己毁了城市而自责
Instead of punishing yourself because you think you destroyed the city,
开始着手拯救这城市怎么样
how about you start by saving it?
一千万美元
$10 million,
我想这是说好的价格
I believe was the negotiated amount.
恭喜  你现在进入新的纳税阶层了
Congratulations, you're now in a new tax bracket.
只是出于好奇
Just out of curiosity,
你付给我一千万美元  那你能得到...
you pay me ten million, and you get...
这价钱的三倍
Three times that.
你已经有买家了
You already have a buyer?
我建议你远离马库维亚几个月
I recommend that you stay clear of Markovia for a few months.
我想我们的生意到此结束了
I believe our business is now concluded.
还没有
Not yet.
看起来你的搭档抛弃你了
Looks like your partner abandoned you.
他不是我的搭档
He's not my partner.
他是我雇来做事的
He's someone I hired to do a job.
看来这笔钱花的值
And it turns out it was money well spent.
趴下太愚蠢了
Just too dumb to stay down.
别那么做
Don't do it!
你会杀死这里的所有人
You'll kill everyone here.
如果我不把这仪器送到马库维亚的买家手里
If I don't deliver this device to my buyer in Markovia,
我也一样死定了
I'm dead anyway.
不
No!
罗伊  我需要你的帮助
Roy, I need your help.
罗伊  马上住手
Roy, stop right now!
-罗伊  -混蛋
- Roy. - Son of bitch.
罗伊  罗伊  住手
Roy! Roy, I need you to stop!
地震仪器就在里面
The earthquake device is in there.
这钢是军事级别的  能抵挡炸弹
The steel is military grade; it's built to withstand a bomb,
但是抵挡不了你
but not you.
想想西娅
Think about Thea.
如果没有你的帮助  她可能会死
Because she could die without your help.
我知道你爱她...
I know you love her...
因为我看见了
Because I've seen it.
救救我的妹妹
Save my sister.
控制住
Control.
集中注意力想西娅
Focus on Thea.
她现在需要你
She needs you right now,
否则她就会死
or she is dead.
所有人都会死
Everyone is dead.
你是...
You're...
对  没错
Yeah. Yeah.
去年  你救了我的命
Last year, you saved my life.
我不是说从绑架我的人手里
And I don't mean from the guy who kidnapped me.
我是说  你...
I mean, you...
你拯救了我
you saved me.
你给了我目标
You gave me purpose.
我们才刚刚开始
We're just getting started.
所以...秘密组织有了个新成员
So...the secret society gets a new member.
他现在在哪
Where is he now?
在家
Home.
他还在...
He's, uh...
消化这事
processing.
当我知道你的真实身份时
When I found out who you really were,
我吃了一品脱的薄荷片才接受这个事实
I processed my way through a pint of mint chip.
我压力大就吃东西
I stress eat.
说到压力...
Speaking of stress...
我不是想开周一例会  今天周三
I'm not trying to Monday morning quarterback here--it's Wednesday.
这一切不都是因为你担心
Didn't this all start because you were worried
罗伊的力量会被坏人利用吗
that Roy's marble collection was on the short side?
她说得有理  奥利弗
She has a point, Oliver.
罗伊是匹野马  现在他知道你的秘密了
Roy's a loose cannon. Now he knows your secret.
你说得对
You're right,
但我没考虑后果
and I wasn't thinking about the consequences.
我只知道我需要他的力量
I only knew that I needed his strength.
他的力量
His power.
在岛上
On the island,
莎拉告诉我爱是最强大的情感
Sara told me that love is the most powerful emotion.
绿箭侠不能让罗伊想到西娅
Well, the Arrow couldn't get Roy to think about Thea.
但我可以
But I could.
我说了后退
I said get back!
想想莎朵
Think about Shado.
我在...
I am...
想着她
thinking about her!
我得告诉你一件关于莎朵的事
There's something I have to tell you about Shado.
是一件你需要知道的事
It's something you deserve to know.
她爱你  斯莱德
She loved you, Slade.
也许不是以你想要的方式
Maybe not the way that you wanted her to,
但她爱你
but she loved you.
而且她想让你回家
And she wanted you to make it home.
她想让你再见到乔
She wanted you to see Joe again.
她想让你拥抱你的儿子
She wanted you to hug your son.
我知道你很愤怒
I know you're angry.
我也知道你想复仇
And I know you want revenge.
如果你毁了艾沃的货船
If you destroy Ivo's freighter,
莎朵就白白牺牲了
Shado will have died for nothing.
我到底怎么了
What is happening to me?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不会让你一个人
I am not going to let you go through it
承受这些的
on your own.
杀了莎朵的那个人
The man who killed Shado
还没被抓到
is still out there.
而不管那艘货船沉没没有
And whether that freighter's on the bottom of the ocean or not,
我们都还被困在这个岛上
we're still stuck on this island.
不会很久的
Not for long.
因为我们要乘那艘货船回家
Because we're going to take the freighter.
很高兴收到你的邮件
I was glad to receive your email.
是不是跟我想的一样
Does it portend what I'm hoping?
我要去参加竞选
I'm going to run.
是什么让你改变主意的
What changed your mind?
西娅
Thea.
她提醒我我还欠这座城市的
She reminded me that I still owe this city.
我想被世人铭记  而不是作为
And I want to be remembered as something more
马尔科姆·梅林的傀儡
than Malcolm Merlyn's pawn.
你应该被人记住
As you should.
但你知道我的犹豫还有别的原因
But you know there was another reason for my reticence.
你害怕别人知道
You're afraid the people will learn
罗伯特不是她的亲生父亲
that Robert wasn't her biological father.
我设法在不说出
I managed to get through a
真相的情况下通过了审判
criminal trial without the truth coming out,
但政治选举能更容易地挖出
but political campaigns tend to be a bit more adept
一个人罪恶的秘密
at extracting skeletons from closets.
但没有别人知道
But no one else knows.
有人知道
Someone does.
我的妇产科医生  吉尔医生
My OB, Dr. Gill.
西娅出生时情况很复杂
There were complications when Thea was born,
我不得不告诉他罗伯特不是她父亲
And I had to tell him that Robert wasn't her father.
如果我们要发展下去
If we're going to move forward,
我们得确定
we need to make certain
他不会成为我们的问题
that he won't be a problem for us.
特纳先生
Mr. Turner.
我不知道这里还允许配偶探视
I didn't know this place allowed conjugal visits.
我叫阿曼达·沃勒
My name is Amanda Waller.
你说的好像你很有名
You say that like it's supposed to mean something.
正好相反
To the contrary.
我的身份是高度机密
My identity is highly classified.
那你为什么向我做自我介绍
Then why are you introducing yourself to me?
我有个工作机会给你
I have an offer for you.
一个让你减刑的方法
A way to work off your sentence.
事实证明  我需要一个像你一样...
As it turns out, I have need of someone with your...
天赋异禀的人
singular qualifications.
为了什么
For what?
为了一支我正在组建的部队
For a unit I'm putting together.
什么样的部队
What type of unit?
实际上...
Actually...
更像是一支小队
It's more of a squad.
我知道了你的秘密你会杀了我吗
Is this the part where you kill me 'cause I know your secret?
你觉得我会杀了我妹妹的男朋友吗
Do you actually think that I'd kill my sister's boyfriend?
可你曾经往我腿上射了一箭
Well, you did shoot me in the leg.
不过我已经原谅你了
Forgiven, by the way.
西娅
Thea.
永远不能让她知道
She can never know.
我觉得如果我告诉她的话
I get the feeling that if I did tell her,
你真的会杀了我
that would be when you kill me.
相信你的直觉
Trust that instinct.
好吧
Ok. All right.
有多少人知道
How many people know what--
你是谁
who you are?
很多
Too many.
但只有这两个比较重要
But these are the only two that matter.
约翰·狄格尔和费利西蒂·斯莫克
John Diggle and Felicity Smoak.
这个团队有名字吗
Does this group have a name?
比如绿箭队之类的
Like Team Arrow, or something?
我们不那么称呼自己
We don't call ourselves that.
我会  偶尔会
I do. Occasionally.
-停  -无所谓
- Stop.  - Whatever.
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard.
莎拉...
Sara...